Chayn Privacy policy
====================

**  
  
Use of private information policy (GDPR)**  
_Last updated: \[October 2021\].  
‍_  
Chayn CIO, a charity registered in the United Kingdom (charity number: 1196098) (hereinafter referred to as “**Chayn**”, “**we**”, “**us**” or “**our**”) operates [https://chayn.co/](https://chayn.co/) which crowdsources and publishes resources to help victims of domestic abuse.  
  
This Privacy Policy explains how Chayn, as data controller, will process any personal data that we may collect about you as a visitor to [https://chayn.co/](https://chayn.co/). If you have additional questions or require more information about our Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact us at team@chayn.co.  
  
**How is your personal data collected?**  
  
**Information that you give to us**  
We collect, process and use your personal information when you:  
\- sign up to our mailing list via our website or through our apps;  
\- contact us by email or through our website;  
\-fill out forms out on our website;  
\-sign up to volunteer with us; and  
\-interact with us on Little Window, our chatbot.  
\-sign up for an account on our services (Soul Medicine, Bloom and YSM)  
‍  
**The information we collect includes**:  
\-your name and title;  
\-phone number and email address;  
\-social media details (if you have provided them to us);  
\-your country and city of residence;  
\-information you provide through Little Window, our chatbot;  
\- time and day you used Little Window,  
\- business name (if applicable).  
We may save other details you provide when signing up for an account with Soul medicine or Bloom or YSM  
  
**Information we collect from other sources  
  
‍**We may also receive information about you from social media platforms including but not limited to when you interact with us on those platforms or access our social media content. The information we may receive is governed by the privacy settings, policies, and/or procedures of the applicable social media platform, and we encourage you to review them.  
‍  
**Cookies and similar tools  
‍**Most of our websites do not use cookies or scripts designed to track the websites you visit. Where they do, your consent will be expressly requested with a link to our cookies policy**.  
‍  
How we use the information we collect  
‍**We use the information we collect:  
\- to respond to your enquiries;  
\-to send you our newsletters;  
\-to allow you to volunteer with us;  
\-to send you details of our products and services; and  
\-to comply with legal obligations to which we are subject and cooperate with regulators and law enforcement authorities.  
\-to send you the content you have requested from our products and services;  
\-to improve the services we provide to you.  
‍  
**Legal bases for using your personal information  
  
‍**There are different legal bases that we rely on to use your personal data, namely:  
  
‍**Performance of a contract** – The use of your personal information may be necessary to perform the contract that you have with us. For example, if you purchase products from our website, we will use your personal information to provide you with such products.  
  
‍**Consent** – We may obtain your consent to collect and use certain types of personal information when we are required to do so by law (for example, in relation to our direct marketing activities).  
  
‍**Legitimate interests** – We may use your personal information for our legitimate interests, for example, to respond to your enquiries made via the website. When we process personal information to meet our legitimate interests, we put in place robust safeguards to ensure that your privacy is protected and to ensure that our legitimate interests are not overridden by your interests or fundamental rights and freedoms.  
  
**How we may share the information we collect  
  
‍**We may share the information we collect, including your personal information, with third parties under the following circumstances:  
  
**Service providers and business partners**. We may share your personal information with our service providers and business partners that perform marketing services and other business operations for us. These companies are authorised to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.  
  
**With Law enforcement agency, court, regulator**, government authority or other third party. We may share your personal information with these parties where we believe this is necessary to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation, or otherwise to protect our rights or the rights of any third party. Where permitted by law or regulation and reasonably practicable, we will attempt to notify you of such requirements.  

**International transfers  
‍**In managing our business we may transfer your personal data outside of the EU.Where we transfer your personal data to countries outside of the EU which are yet to be subject to a finding of adequacy, we put in place appropriate safeguards in accordance with applicable legal requirements to ensure that your personal data is adequately safeguarded and protected. For more information on the appropriate safeguards in place and to obtain a copy of such safeguards, please contact us at the contact information set out below.  
  
**How we protect the personal data we collect  
‍**We implement technical and organisational measures to ensure a level of security appropriate to the risk to the personal data we process. These measures are aimed at ensuring the on-going integrity and confidentiality of personal information.  
  
‍**How long we will retain your personal data  
‍**We retain the information collected via our website for as long as required to fulfil the purpose for which the data was collected.  For example, we will retain contact details when you subscribe to our newsletter until you choose to unsubscribe. For Soul Medicine and YSM, it is until you ask us to delete you from our database. For Bloom, chat transcripts are stored for 6 months but booking details are kept for longer.  
  
**  
Rights with respect to your personal data  
‍**You can unsubscribe or opt-out of receiving marketing communications from us by unsubscribing to our newsletters or contacting us using the details at the end of this Privacy Policy.  
  
Subject to local law, you may have certain rights regarding information that we have collected and that is related to you.You can ask us:  
  
\- to access your personal data;  
\- that information we hold about you be updated or rectified;  
\- to erase your personal information;  
\- to provide you or a third party with a copy of certain personal data about you (referred to as the right of “data portability”); and  
\- to restrict our use of your personal information.  
Please note that we may require additional information from you in order to fulfill your requests  
  
.If you would like to discuss or exercise such rights, send us an email at team@chayn.co. We also encourage you to contact us to update or correct your information if it changes or if you believe that any information that we have collected about you is inaccurate.  
  
Alternatively, you may have a right to complain to your local data protection authority (if one exists in your country).  For example, in the UK individuals have the right to complain to the Information Commissioners Office about the use of your personal data.  
  
**Content license  
‍**All of Chayn’s products and services are under a Creative Commons or MIT License. This does not cover the products of other organisations.  
  
**Third party websites  
‍**Our site includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from our practices. If you submit personal data to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any sites to which our website provides links. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any website you visit.  
  
**Changes to this Privacy Policy  
‍**We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time.  The effective date of the current Privacy Policy is noted at the top of this page. We encourage you to periodically review this page.  
  
**Other policies**  
1. [Equal opportunities and anti-oppression policy](https://www.chayn.co/policies/equal-opportunities-and-anti-oppression-policy)  
**‍**

**How to contact us**
---------------------

If you would like to contact us with questions about our privacy or data protection practices, please contact us at privacy@chayn.co or by post at:  
‍_Chayn CIC  
3rd Floor 86-90 Paul Street  
London, EC2A 4NE  
United Kingdom_
